[Music]
so my co-founder and CTO it goes like
that IO I'm also one of the core
contributors to react natives
if you are using react natives probably
know me from announcing magnetic
releases and publishing change looks and
today I'm here to talk about bundlers
how they work and how they relate to
react native I feel like it's kind of a
bit of you know hard topic is the first
stock but I'm really hoping you guys
will kind of enjoy it so let's start
with the most fundamental question what
a bundler really is how many of you have
an idea what the bungalow is please
raise your hand all right so like 60 50
more or less so this might be the most
educational presentation I've ever made
so far so I really feel like I hope that
you guys will enjoy those graphs I kind
of put a lot of effort to make that look
nice but I really kind of feel bad about
them anyway but yeah it's like bundler
is a tool that simply takes all your
joyous source files and put them into
one file right and that process is
called bundling there are many of them
these days with webpack or browserify
the most popular so we are probably not
wondering why do we need that right like
why do we even need to merge all the
files each one so to better understand
us let's step back to early days of web
and see how the things used to be so
historically JavaScript hasn't had any
standards for requiring dependencies
from your code there was no import or
required statements available so how did
we make functions of our code visible to
the outer world or how would how did we
import first part Kovach code to to our
applications the only way was through
global variable right so for example if
you wanted to jQuery which was pretty
common those days you'll go ahead and
add a strict stack that blows it from
external resource as a result your
global scope would get populated with
its bin
things in this case at the lower side so
one can say that this is actually neat
right all said with just a few lines of
code however imagine this scenario your
prototype works out your application
grows and you end up looking into
splitting your file to smaller reusable
pieces so you would end up with
something like this now the code will
get executed and the script tag should
have access to all the global variables
as defining the proceeding file the
problem here is the order
what if you jes wanted to depend on
barges go you'd have to change the order
right and manipulating the other scale
can lead you to weird issues and it's
more like a it's kind of similar to call
box health and I often call it a script
code so how do we solve it
turns out it was already solved in other
environment like for example in ODS that
implements its own module system using
require functions any sport object
amongst other things up top on top of
the common J's
module specs so what if we could do the
same in our front end code that would be
great right however there is one
technical limitation here the require
itself is synchronous in node.js
environment it's fine right because when
you want to load a file it's kind of
physically available next to the file
you're already in so that's easy
however in context of web you need to
make an HTTP request to load a file that
has never been processed by the browser
yet and the other request is aging so
the solution is simple you can bundle
all the files and so on so that we have
them in memory at the time the required
function being cold and that's the
primary reason for you know the bundling
explained in under five minutes
so bundlers can be perceived as a
natural evolution of task runners that
we know like cows and grunt that
happened over the course a few years
there are lots of responsibilities in
scope for them rather than just getting
your code bundled into one chunk for the
sake of organizing
one of them for example in translation a
typical bundler can or has support for
transpiling your code that means for
reading it but source in particular
format for example in new at JS spec and
outputting it in an older supported form
of like es5 the most popular out there
is bubble and most bundlers out here
provide a first-class integration of it
so we mentioned already that in order
for required to work your entire
application has to be loaded into memory
that code is your bundle size to
increase and ship with models and
doesn't necessarily need to be loaded on
the initial page run right so code
splitting is a feature that allows you
to split your curl into various bundles
which can then be load it on demand or
in parallel and in es2015 compatible
environment for example you could resume
for function to obtain an instance of a
module the promise is resolved as soon
as the loading process is finished and
the instance of the module is available
and the last feature that is worth
mentioning is the code magnification for
example web pack 2 has suffered a poor
tree shaking that means it can determine
what parts of your modules are not used
for example you don't use one function
of the full module and effectively
remove those parts from the bundle
combined with other minifiers
like abilify it can contribute to
smaller bundle sizes that gets delivered
to users so that's the bit of that's a
bit of fury now how does that all relate
to react native we are at the remedy
conference so the talk should be purely
about where native stuff so we read
natives we express our native mobile
apps by writing JavaScript and layout by
writing react component however both iOS
language has no way to run JavaScript
right they are distinct platforms
they're all languages and occasion tools
so there is no easy way to do it by
default however those all platforms have
one thing in common which is the ability
to spin a J's VM that can process and
execute your code and react need does
that and then sets up a bi-directional
data flow that is called the bridge
which is a layer that can accept an
arbitrary JavaScript call it can forward
it to the native module and get back
some results so the use of J's VM is
what makes the constraints we just suck
in context of web applicable here as
well so just to give you a great example
for example on iOS react native uses
JavaScript code to execute your
application bundle its features and
performance change in persistent basis
that means you'll get a different
JavaScript expect supported on your Mac
then on iOS 8 9 and 10 devices tsardom
is like more or less for environments
that your code can be running it so we
definitely want to transpile that to the
lowest subset supported on all those
devices so sounds like react native is
pretty similar to web right we have
access to some of the same polyfills
Global's api's language and spec are
also the same we bundle killed the same
ways there are even modules on NPM that
work involving viruses however there is
only one thing that's fundamentally
different and it's the react native
start command that we run every day at
first glance all it does is it served
your application bundle at the given URL
that can be accessed on your local HUD
pretty simple right so why don't we use
for example web pack and configure it to
do exactly the same alight experiment so
I feel like why I'm not doing it so I
like web packs for the fact that it has
a nice declarative interface which is
its web pack counting so what I did in
first place is I created an empty comfy
where I could just point to an entry
file and define some other settings for
react native to load the bundle then I
thought of all related specific features
as I knew about and I try to suffer them
in order for my prototype to work so one
of them was of course the death server
creative works by loading your bundle
from the URL in most cases is the name
of your entry point plus that platform
that bundle extension and it works by
default on 4th
8081 so you definitely want to do it the
same way then I had to integrate bubble
of course to transpile es6 and whatever
I had to run on my iOS device and by
default react native does that to your
entire node module including even those
that don't need it which gives it some
weird issues like recently with the 0.46
released so to make my experiment
backwards-compatible I decided to
conditionally why place all modules that
start with free acts name so for example
react native or anyway native plugins
would get transposed on slides there is
also expo because I was using some of
their navigation solutions and last but
not least to make my platform specific
code to run I just reserve that
extensions to define the order file
should be the result when I'm calling
require so in this case I wanted my
implementation to long first from
specific file the native file and then
end up well loading just a giant file
and finally the most entertaining part
was supporting Facebook proprietary no
haste system now if you don't know it
it works by you inverse by annotating
any file you want which provides module
and then that file can be globally
required across the entire project by
its name that way you can have them
spread across the entire repo without
thinking where they are so that's what
Facebook is or used to be using
internally and that's the reason why
it's kind of leaked to react native and
its present dirt so of course web pack
has no idea how to support it and what
it will try to do is it will try to get
those modules from your module but since
we don't have them we'll end up with an
error so we definitely want to somehow
overcome this but has a great
feature which is the result that is it
is a map where keys are name of the
modules that can be globally required
and values are absolute paths where
those files are located so my solution
turns to be quite down but perfect in
terms of performance I just decided to
go for all J's files across the folder
check the dog blog and even
was provides module inside I was just
assuming it's a no haze file so after of
hacking use it for a few nights I
finally got it running in less than
seven seconds with Park created and
served a bundle and for the URL that I
want I said great nothing but
declarative with accounting and I ruled
the world but my excitement went away as
soon as I realized that opening a mobile
app actually results in the red screen
I've noticed lots of our images were not
showing app life reload wasn't working
at all
debugging from started producing red
screens and by the time I didn't really
know what run time is operating men more
importantly red screen messages started
looking weird the structure ace was
unreadable it's even unreadable here
anyway but it was kind of impossible to
locate original file because it was
saying index that bundle and you know
some minified lines so kind of crazy to
the back so I started to realize that in
context of react natives there has to be
more than just about dealer that is
running turns out running great native
start spins up entire set of tools that
are focused on providing you with a
better developer experience editor there
is a source that bundler all the rest
are just complementary features build on
top of it and I call it a packager I
know it might be confusing with react
native packager but since it's recently
changed the name to Metro I decided to
sue it for the sake of this slide so
packager is a tool that is used to
develop debug and package an entire
application it builds on top of an
arbitrary bundler like web pack and
ships with pre-configured set of
transforms and settings required for
your code to run in this environment so
I decided to keep my experiment going
and see if I can make web pack work with
react native the plans to support all
these features including some links that
never were to create native before now
there were there were many rig react
native and web bug integrations before
that would react native web box server
being one of them if I remember but the
problem in those words that there was
still package or running in the
background the way they were set up was
that web bug was processing your killed
first and then giving it to packager to
process the final bundle what we wanted
to do here is we wanted to get
completely without packager or anything
related to packager and just use webpack
and whatever whatever there wasn't PMS
whoa so in particular I was interested
in the boundary whereas the words the
boundary between react native did the
bundler and the rest of the tools and I
was wondering how many things I will
have to write on top of web bug in order
to make it fully working with react
native so the fear the first thing I
started looking into us the chrome
debugger on standard react native app
learning that mode opens a new tab in
your browser however there is there is
no there are no api's on iOS or on
Android for openings chrome taps on
other computer right so I quickly
realized that it has to be a package
error that is opening up Chrome not
react native device and since the
package there is a process running on a
host machine it has access to all the
native API that are required for this
action to be done so the only thing that
was left was to figure out how do those
two pieces talk to each other and turns
out packager is an HTTP server it is
composed out of standalone middle words
each having a different responsibility
together they form a tool that provides
the developer experience we know from
react native it's really cool and
powerful concept we enables the plugins
play certain parts as middle words makes
it very customizable as hackable as you
can see the last this is actually the
code that I just copied from
latest react native like few days ago
the last
middleware here is the package or server
which is the Metro bundler
where native users and the rest are just
the things added on top like status page
manure or OpenStack frame in edit or
middleware and other things like that
and the communication is established by
react native calling package or endpoint
then the handler is executing procedure
on the host machine and refers back to
react native client of the status as you
can see it's very similar to remote
procedural coal that we know from
distributed computing with a small
difference that everything happens on
your local health so in order to get my
project rolling instead of spawning
wetbacks from common blind and relying
purely on its country I decided to use
Express server and web bugs as we work
for that that way I could still get an
instance of an HTTP server and combine
that with the powerful confident web
pack hat so after I got it working that
way I started to rewrite and add in the
missing middle-earth
so let's just go over for some of them
that I had to reinstall and create or
just copy one of them is the life reload
middleware and as the name indicates
this is the middle word that's
responsible for life reloading your app
right you have this feature in your
mobile devices on your mobile devices
you open dev tools and you see life
eternal life is loading once you turn it
on every time you change this file your
app automatically reloads
so the way it works is once it's
activated react native sense a
longer-lasting get request to the
packager on such request the middleware
stores the response object associated
with particular requests as soon as
changes happen to files in your file
system for example in this case I can
attach done event on compiler compiler
is an instance of web pack all
connections are going to be closed with
changed through payload that indicates
that the client in this case read native
device should reload itself now that we
have a better understanding of how the
communication between package and react
native is done we can look into solving
those thread screens that we had
previously one of them was the run
technology and the second was the Battle
of messages so I'm quite excited about
that one because the ability to use an
arbitrary browser to run and back the
business logic of my mobile app was like
pure
when I first heard about it so what
happens is as soon as you turn on chrome
debugger from the Bessel's react native
executed remote procedure to launch that
salt inside chrome tab is necessary
right after both device and debugger
connect with each other by using
WebSocket connection since there is no
way for them to connect directly because
we are dealing with a chrome tab with
its own limitations and device they have
to use packager which acts as a
WebSocket proxy between them and if for
some reason the connection can be
established you end up with run tagging
already exceptions that you can often
see so once all well and good WebSocket
executors on the device since the JSON
message to the chrome tab it is a JSON
object and it has to contain at least a
missile property it tells the bugger
which handler to execute the rest of the
keys varies on the handle of bases in
this case we are this is the first
payload that's ever called for the
WebSocket connection and it's to execute
application script it's so-called a
special handler because it's hard-coded
in the debugger what it does is it takes
everything that's inside injects it
parses it and then it puts it on a
global object so that you can access the
global you later and the next thing it
does is it uses web worker import
scripts to load to synchronously load
JavaScript at given URL into the scope
of the web worker and then the execution
proceeds normally but if given method is
not a special case handler it's handled
each handler will be looked up at the
edge debug bridge and executed so the
communication pattern that you just seen
is pretty much the same when you are
using javascript core on iOS device the
difference is that instead of using web
socket executors you are using JSP
executors
historically they're also used to be
webview executors that was used for
debugging of Safari once I got the
bugger app running I started looking
into those with error messages
now I didn't include that in my initial
prototype when I was working on that
integration a Steve Kellogg from in
kindred contributed it later thank you
for that however I find it very
interesting so I decided to describe it
also in this in your slides so what
happens is that as soon as there is an
error reg native asks packager to sit
colligate you're stuck trace if you ever
had a red screen you probably noticed
that after a millisecond the factory
changes like certain changes are like
there is like a change and that's why
that because of that async request that
happens in the background so what
happens is as soon as we get that
request with the payload the rules that
we'll explore later we create the first
thing we do is we create an instance of
source map consumer we passed the roast
or flop as for example res from the file
system in this case I removed it for the
sake of making it smaller however the
code for that can be found on github and
source Maps roasting was just taken out
from the web web pack memory file system
so source map consumer represents a
power source of objects that we can use
for looking at the original details
about the file location and other things
that we want to do we then map the
reckless request body which is an array
of all the frames for the error that we
got on the device to the original source
lines and column information that we get
by squaring source map consumer in such
a way is then sent back to react native
and replace on the red screen and that's
why you see the difference so the reason
I'm telling you this is I believe that
bundler implementation should be
pluggable the package are enriched
native does way more things than just
compiling your code and those things are
not treated right so they were carefully
designed over the course of months and
from my experience it took me like two
weeks to implement wetbacks were quick
native and I still got a lot of bugs to
deal with if the entire platform is
pluggable it would have been way easier
but do we really need that like what's
wrong with
three amazing packager bender in the
world let me answer this question by
asking you another one do you want
siblings lack of support fourth of them
was prolong one of the most common
issues with react native development
especially for library output related
promised us the workflow we know from
web and no GES and brought it to the
world of mobile development however
breaking that expectation was painful
for many people now it is because the
default metro bundler uses Watchmen to
listen profile changes and react
accordingly now watch man is a facebook
open source library constraint to
provide maximum performance when it
comes down to listening for changes in
your file system
one of its limitations for the sake of
speed is that it doesn't change doesn't
listen for changes in similar locations
and it's not clear whether this feature
will get implemented each other and it's
perfectly fine because the Facebook
scale lots of milliseconds that seem
irrelevant to us not to reload and now
I'm really like happy and glad that we
get a lot of performance improvements
for free like recently they contributed
a lot of improvements to source map
generation however at the same time I
believe it should be like we should be
able to opt in for a slightly lower
slower solution of more feature-rich and
kind of designed to solve our use cases
that's why it's all time we made whole
how is a drop-in replacement for
existing packager it builds on top of
open tools like web pack at its core we
have the Express server with those
pluggable Needlers it is a shockable dev
server with predictable workflow most of
the code snippet that you have seen
today can be found on the repo so if you
got any questions regarding to the
things that I missed them slide please
check it and here is how it feels you
first select the platform that you want
to prefer bundle for normally you do it
by passing a slack but I guess many of
you have often like mixed flags or
forgot about them I do it all the time
I never remember like how to run on a
remote device always have to check help
and see
was the name of the option so we felt
like instead of exiting with an arrow
we're going to ask you to provide it and
more importantly we're going to show you
how to run it next time so you don't
have to answer it over and over after
the process finishes we just wait for it
to bundle and you're ready to go and we
design it carefully around best
developer experience taking s much
inspiration as possible from community
leaders such as such as people that
contributed to create react app in fact
if you've been using it you can probably
tell that it's very similar and looks
all of the same and there are a couple
of reasons why we might hold two of them
we already mentioned today one of them
was supper for siblings something that
we wanted to die for especially in our
monorail kind of setup and the second
was to embrace potential of plug ability
and make something that can be extended
in a really easy way and the last one
was that web pack is just awesome
now I was I was thinking about this
slide for awhile because I'm not gonna
lie when I was riding home I ended up
like almost killing myself trying to
understand how to write plug-ins for
website because of dogs the res is great
I like the dog very much however it's
like if you really want to understand
web bug you have to write a plugin then
it will go over all the repos check out
the source code and then you will
understand it man it's still awesome and
people who made it are also awesome
because they came up with those
abstractions and what I like about it is
that its extensive well-documented
interface and it has a very broad
ecosystem it opens a lot of exciting
possibilities for us we can even like I
don't know think of some crazy things
like writing CSS to style your real gaps
so rate native apps for example if you
are not a fan of inline styles or I
don't know like using side screens or
some other weird loaders one of the
common issues in the past was that
people wanted to use JSX
and that extension wasn't supported by
radix packager web.config it's like one
line of code and also if you are already
using webpack in the web it gives you
perfect opportunity to share your code
things like oh yeah
or I don't know like changing extensions
of our platform basis those are just
nice helpers that can help you to write
a cross-platform universal app and there
are lots of features missing that we are
working on currently our top priority is
to increase its adoption so that we get
more bug report and we can make it
faster and better if the idea of host
sounds interesting to you or you wanted
to use it please do it and let me know
what your what's your opinion what's
your what are your ideas whether it
works for your now and we'll do our best
to make it work for you and as I
mentioned I'm really looking into making
a whole a platform for other bundlers to
run their faster or maybe different
alternatives to web bug that can work
for you I like used bus or metro bundler
and I believe that one should be able to
use whatever works for him to bundle the
app and still get the first-class user
experience and developer experience that
whole gives you thank you
[Applause]